Good afternoon
Добрый день
Good evening put the scissors away from me I'm
Добрый вечер отложите ножницы от мне
scared
страшно
they cut
они порезали
live I'm a blogger from Ukraine the
прямом эфире Я вот блогер из Украины
city of Khmelnitsky You are from the
город Хмельницкий Вы откуда
Pskov region
Псковской области
closer to Estonia or closer to the Baltics you can
ближе к Эстонии или ближе к можно
say
сказать
support special military operations
поддержите специальную военные операции
If I understood what the target was I do
Если бы я понимал что там за цель Я даже
n't even know what  there, they didn’t give support for the goals.
не знаю что там за цели то поддержите не
Most likely
Скорее всего нет чем понял
, I didn’t understand, some of them also had boys
некоторые были у меня тоже пацанчики
who say that we don’t know the goals, we
которые говорят что цели не знаем мы
support because our country
поддерживаем потому что наша страна
[music]
[музыка]
but the meaning is yes,
а смысл да
and you specifically chose chat roulette from Ukraine by
а вы в чат рулетку от Украины специально
accident  then it’s interesting Just
А для чего тогда интересно Просто
interesting to talk with people
интересно с людьми пообщаться
about the whole principle About their moods Well,
обо всем принципе Об их настроениях Ну
let me get you ask me something
давайте я попался спрашивайте мне что-то
about my mood Yes, I usually don’t
про настроение Да я обычно ничего не
ask anything right away they start bombing and you
спрашиваю сразу начинают бомбить и вы
immediately understand
сразу понимаете
No there right away Not all [ __ ] are
Нет там сразу Не все же придурки
normal So 80 percent is adequate here
нормально Так 80 процентов адекватно вот
I got caught adequately so yet You
я попался адекватно так еще Вот вы
wanted to talk to me Yes, I usually
хотели со мной поговорить да я обычно
don’t say anything I
ничего не говорю
ask the topic  t
тему задают
And what topics do you need
А какие вам темы
Well, they also ask sometimes they ask
Ну вот тоже спрашивают иногда спрашивают
for whom for Russia or for Ukraine you still
за кого за Россию или за Украину еще
answer a
отвечаете
football match that somewhere we are
футбольный матч что где-то идет
sick there, come on Come on Russia, come on
болеем там давай Давай Россия давай
Ukraine Yes, nothing answers the question is a
Украина Да ничего не отвечает вопрос
stupid question people are dying on both sides
тупой вопрос люди умирают с обеих сторон
of something to get sick  It’s just that I don’t understand
чем-то болеть Я просто вот я не понимаю
then that’s the meaning of your stay in those
тогда вот смысл вашего пребывания в те
Turkish people from a conversation with Ukraine, that is, an
турец с разговора с Украиной то есть
inner feeling of guilt you want to
внутреннее чувство вины вы хотите
talk to people, you just don’t
поговорить с людьми просто вообще не
want any guilt at all
хочет чувство вины вообще никакого А вот
I can explain I
Вы же выбрали Россию я могу объяснить Я
want I specifically ask people about the
хочу я специально спрашиваю людей про
war I argue with them about the war about
войну спорю с ними про войну про
politics i.e.
политику то есть
Let's ask something Maybe
Давайте спросить что-нибудь Может
we can bet no So you don't support a
поспорим нет Так вы же не поддерживаете
special operation What to argue with you
специального на операцию Что с вами
No I have some
спорить Нет у меня есть некоторые
points of contention let's go
спорные моменты давайте давайте
on now  we will unpack
сейчас на вас распакуем
some of you. For example, they
некоторые Например
immediately ask why you came to us, a
сразу спрашивают зачем вы к нам пришли
logical question to answer this if the
логичный вопрос на это ответить если
answer is of course Dava  let's
ответить конечно Давайте Давайте
try it like this,
попробуем так
experts attention the question is why did you come to us
знатоки внимание вопрос зачем вы к нам
and you are striving Well, yes, I’ll immediately say I’m a
а вы стремите Ну да я сразу скажу я же
blogger like a streamer It’s clear my
блогер типа стриме Понятно моя задаю
question And whose Crimea is Ukrainian Well Ukrainian is
вопрос А чей Крым Ну украинский это
definitely Ukrainian you want to
однозначно украинский вы хотите его
take it back and back in the sense So we have this
забрать и обратно в смысле Так у нас это
time  occupy now it's not your
время оккупировать сейчас он не Ваш
sense
смысле
here you have a phone it's yours
вот вас есть телефон он Ваш
if I take it and put it in my pants
если я его заберу и засуну себе в штаны
whose phone it is
чей это телефон
Well until I get back your
Ну пока я не заберу обратно ваш
phone which I stole it's true but it's
телефон который я украл правда но это
your phone
ваш телефон
There is such a topic as long as there is something
Есть такая тема пока есть что-то
legal around  let’s say that the legal
правовое вокруг этого допустим правовое
state gave my state in
государство дал мой государство в
which this happens is not right, then
котором это происходит не правое то
you can actually say yours, that is, it
можно сказать фактически ваш то есть
turns out that the
получается
world lives according to the rules, it recognizes
мир живет же по правилам он признает
Crimea before Ukrainian everyone recognizes it, so I
Крым до украинских все признают вот я бы
wouldn’t say that if all the resolutions
так не сказал если бы все резолюции
in a row were implemented, I would say Yes  the world is
подряд он выполнялись я бы сказал Да мир
legal, since many of these
правовой так как многие из этих
I, in principle, yes Personally, I
я в принципе да Лично я
don’t recognize Russian And what
русский не признают А какие
international organizations
международные организации России
does Russia recognize,
признает
and talk to Russia  Well,
причем с Россией уж говорить про меня ну
you’re like the opinion of a lawyer of Russia.
вы же как бы мнение адвокат России
Wait, you, as a citizen of Russia, a
Подождите вы как гражданин России
citizen, you stand over Russia. Russia
гражданин вы стоите над Россией Россия
over you, you are the source of power in the country.
над вами вы источник власти в стране
Yes, that is, you get
правильно да То есть вы получаете Если
it.  everyone Why
ваша каждый Почему
is it not found that
не встречается
you can squeeze out territories, for example,
можно отжимать территории например
Ukraine can seize the
Украина может себе захватить
Belgorod region for itself, Poland, for example,
Белгородскую область там Польша например
Can you take Kaliningrad there,
Может там Калининград забрать
in principle, yes, if you have enough strength
в принципе да если силёнок хватит Почему
Why not, that is, the philosophy of a gopnik, yes, it
бы и нет то есть философия гопника да
turns out, yes, no, such a world turns out,
получается да нет такой мир получается я
I understand that you will support you
так понимаю что вы поддержите вы
on the contrary  Ukraine, just like well,
напротив Украины примерно так же как ну
America wanted to start a war somewhere
захотела Америка войну начать где-нибудь
to lie there No problems
там врать Нет проблем
unpacked in just a couple of minutes you
распаковали буквально за пару минут вы
don’t support at first Yes a special
сначала не поддерживаете Да специальную
operation support
операцию поддержите
everything you say so
всё что вы говорите так свидетельствует
indicates that you support the war against
о том что вы поддерживаете войну против
Ukraine yes That’s why I just Let’s
Украины да Вот почему я просто Давайте
come back why so asked about the
вернёмся почему так спросил насчёт Крыма
Crimea you
у вас
D  let's go Crimea Russia captured and didn't
Давайте так Крым Россия захватила и не
capture
захватила
captured captured do you think that Crimea
захватил захватила вы считаете что Крым
belongs to Russia or belongs to
принадлежит России или принадлежит
Ukraine
Украине
[music]
[музыка]
actually belongs to Russia who
фактически принадлежит России кому он
should belong to
должен принадлежать
Ukraine or Russia who has the strength to see everything
Украину или России у кого есть сил все
you support forced you are a classic you are a
вы поддержите вынуда вы классическое вы
classic gopnik who No I still  it’s not
классический гопник который Нет я еще не
about
про это
you that the opinion of the Crimeans is not worried about
вас мнение крымчан не волнуется
Crimea, it turns out that you are a classic Gop
Крым получается что вы классический Гоп
Well, you say Who is stronger who are you right,
Ну вы говорите Кто сильнее кто ты прав
you can squeeze Crimea if I am stronger
можно отжать Крым если я сильнее
, we don’t have a court from above that would judge everyone,
у нас нету суда сверху который бы всех
you understand, we are
рассудил понимаешь
waiting for the Americans to give us even more of
ждем чтобы американцы нам еще больше
these morons who came to Ukraine
этих дебилов которые пришли в Украину
all of them will die.
все они сдохнут
Well, the Americans will
Ну всего моряка американцы это дадут
give it to the whole sailor. The Americans give it to us, and we give the awesome Russian stars to
Американ дают нам а мы даем звездюлей
you, they give you exactly as much
русским офигенным вам дают ровно столько
so that it doesn’t continue so that you
чтобы это не продолжал чтобы вы дальше
can’t do anything further, yes, they don’t
ничего не смогли вот да она мерсы не
allow Mercy to shoot at the territory of Russia,
разрешают стрелять по территории России
they knocked out Kharkov and so on now
там Харькова выбили и так далее сейчас
not about it still
не про это все-таки
went too far this time maybe Well
переборщили в этот раз может быть Ну
come on  let's talk about krylchay Let the
давайте давайте про крыльчаем Давайте
Crimeans don't interest you, yes, but someone
крымчан вас не интересует да а кто-то
asked the Crimeans
спрашивал крымчан
Talk to the Crimeans Well, the Crimeans
Поговорите с крымчанами Ну вот крымчане
before for Ukraine
до за Украину
that you didn’t meet such people because
что ты таких не встречала потому что
look during the occupation, that’s when the
смотрите во время оккупации вот когда
Russian troops stopped the raisins Yes,
российские войска купировали изюм Да
there were a lot of those who said no  we
много там было тех кто сказали не мы
went against the Russian troops, the troops left, everything was fine, they began
войска ушли все все нормально стали
to say so, and then how it happened Russia
говорить так и тут как случилось Россия
bought
купила
Donetsk,
Донецке
how there were no repressions Let's show it
как не было никаких репрессий Покажите
like
давайте так
this They forbade these activists
Запрещали активистам этих
at all They forbade them to come
вообще Запрещали Да им приезжать
Where they are now
Где сейчас находится
I don't know Exactly Yes
Я не знаю Вот именно Да
people people must have been there who  I had about the
люди люди должны были там кто имел про
Ukrainian position to run
украинскую позицию убежать
away,
было
but Oleg Sentsov Let this fact Oleg
А Олег сенцов Давайте этот факт Олег
Sentsov know who he is, I know Yes,
сенцов знаете кто такой ну знаю Да вот
he lived in Crimea, Crimean
он жил в Крыму крымчанин
Crimean Yes, his group arrested the
крымчанин Да его группа арестовала
Russian authorities for what they arrested I
Российская власть за что арестовали Я
just don’t remember, I don’t remember
просто не помню вот я тоже не помню
why the Russian authorities should at all
почему вообще Российская власть должна
arrest remember if just like that for
арестовать помни если просто так за
arrested
арестовали
there is no such interesting
нет такого интересного
here is an example for you
вот вам пример
they all ate one person, just a fairly
съели все один человек только достаточно
indicative example of sentsov But the
показательный пример сенцов А ну вот
middle one was quite simply in the Crimea and
средний достаточно просто был в Крыму и
talked on purpose talked to
разговаривал специально разговаривал с
people specially talked to the Crimea
людьми специально разговаривал с Крым
pigs are Tatars
свиньи татарами
one girl only in Yalta honestly
одна девушка только в Ялте честно
said that she would like Ukraine to be here
сказала что она хотел бы чтобы тут была
So everyone will be
Украина Вот и все
knocked out by Russians  troops and you will be surprised
выбьют российские войска и вы удивитесь
so you really won’t be able to come to Crimea
так вы правда не сможете приехать в Крым
so and I’ll come I’ll talk to people I’ll
так а я приеду я пообщаюсь людьми я вам
tell you that I wo
скажу что
n’t be able to come because the border with the
не смогу приехать потому что граница с
Russian Federation will be
Российской Федерацией будут закрыта вы
closed  well, what
спросить менее крымчан хорошо а что
needs to be done along the highway once again
нужно сделать по трассе еще раз еще раз
so that Russia leaves it is necessary that Ukraine
чтобы Россия ушла надо чтобы Украина
does not go there sense of
туда не заходила смысле
climate the territory of the climate of the territory of
климата территория климата территории
Ukraine so Ukraine will restore sooner or
Украины так Украина восстановит рано или
later its jurisdiction over
поздно восстановит свою юрисдикцию над
this territory
этой территории Так вернуться А давайте
talk
разговаривать
about what Russia gets Russian
о том что Россия получает Российская
a  army The personnel army is now destroyed by
армия Кадровая армия уничтожена сейчас
such holes with these mobs that also
такая дырки этими мобиками которые тоже
die in industrial places and Russia
дохнут в промышленных местах и Россия
How many
Сколько уже
eight months has it been losing territories, it
восемь месяцев теряет территории она
falls off Yes, the territories the
отваливается Да убежала территории
occupied
захваченные
territories of Russia have fled, but
территория России правда
now, from the point of view of the Constitution, all
теперь с точки зрения Конституции все
Kherson is the Lost Russian
Херсон это Потерянная Российская
territory.
территория
All of us have not finished yet, we have  at the
Все мы еще не закончил мы имеем данный
moment Yes, we have a precedent, so I
момент Да мы имеем прецедент так вот я
can also how to say Don’t worry
также могу как говорить Не переживайте
Crimea, look, Russian troops have come,
Крым смотрите пришли российские войска
occupied, annexed to Russia, so
оккупировали присоединили к России так
everything Ukraine has squeezed back Kherson, it’s pressing
всё Украина отжала назад Херсон это жмёт
Crimea absolutely, you’ll do it
Крым абсолютно это ещё вы сделаете
again Russia will press Kherson back accounting
Россия обратно отожмет Херсон учет
,
хорошо
talk well, this is the future
разговаривать это будущее
What are the trends I  look Here, let's do
Какие тенденции я смотрю Вот давайте как
interpolation or extrapolation in mathematics,
в математике интерполяция или
for example. We take a
экстраполяция например Мы берем тут
point here here a point graph and we can
точка тут точка график и мы можем
see Where this graph will go
посмотреть Куда этот график будет идти
yes we can predict the point So here
да можем предугадать точку Так и тут
look if Russia rolled
смотрите если Россия откатывалась
back rolled back rolled back for 8 months
откатывалась откатываться на 8 месяцев
rolled back What are the previous  sendings to the fact
откатывается Какие предпосылки к тому
that it will start to attack now
что она начнёт наступать теперь
what will happen that will break the situation
что случится такое что приломет ситуацию
Well tell me interestingly
Ну скажите мне интересно
they want to come But now they just don’t
захотят наступает А вот сейчас просто не
want to retreat now they want to retreat yes
хотят сейчас хотят отступать да
now dick understand that
сейчас хер пойми что сейчас
now you have 8 months or how much dick understand
у вас 8 месяцев или сколько хер пойми
what are the prerequisites for what what  something
что какие предпосылки к тому что что-то
should change and your [ __ ] understanding will
должно измениться и ваша хрен поймешь
turn into something understandable But I don’t
тут превратится что-то понятное А я не
understand the goal, you know what you don’t
понимаю цель вот знаете какие вы не
understand in the
понимаешь
ninety-first year, that is, the
девяносто первого года то есть
restoration of control over the
восстановление контроля над
occupied parts of the Luhansk
оккупированными частями Луганской
Donetsk region and Crimea,
Донецкой области и Крыма
and that’s all we have, all our goals are all a  further, the
и все у нас все у нас цели все а дальше
goal of the collapse of Russia, yes, because the
цель развала России да потому что
Russian Federation will begin turmoil
Российская Федерация начнется смута
after losing, it already begins
после проигрыша она уже у вас начинается
in your future Correctly Because we all
в будущем Правильно Потому что мы
look at you in the past, you live in
смотрите вы все в прошлом живете в
some kind of Russian Empire And we are in the
какой-то в Российской империи А мы в
future We live on the ruins of the Russian
будущем Мы живем на руинах Российской
Empire so the Russian Federation
империи так Российской Федерации
I
Я
calculated when it is much ahead,
просчитывал когда она много вперёд
see Russia will fall apart just as the
смотрите Россия развалится также как
Russian Empire is falling apart in
разваливается российской Империя в
1917, after the unsuccessful uh upheaval in
1917 году после неудачных э-э завушки в
World War I Yes, just like the
Первой мировой войне Да также как
Soviet Union collapsed in 91, after the
развалился Советский союз-91 году после
entire Afghan company, and just like the
всей Афганской компании и также как
Russian Federation will fall apart now,
Российская Федерация развалится сейчас у
you already look at you, in fact
вас уже смотреть у вас уже фактически
, it’s already happening We are not talking about the future And now
происходит Мы не про будущее А сейчас
if we talk  you already have republics
если поговорим У вас уже республики
creating their own national armies such
создают национальные свои армии такие
national battalions you have, in addition to the
национальные Батальоны у вас кроме
regular army, which are already
регулярной армии которые уже там
crumbled there yes there are battalions in
покрошена да есть там Батальоны в
Tatarstan battalions in Bashkortostan
Татарстане Батальоны в Башкортостане
battalions in the Republic of Sakha in Chechnya and the
Батальоны в Республике Саха в Чечне с и
army you already have feudal
армия у вас уже идет феодальное
fragmentation with Chechnya I agree with everyone And
дробление с Чечню согласен со всеми А
why  how the battalions in Chechnya differ
почему чем Батальоны в Чечне отличаются
from the battalions in Tatarstan
от батальонов Татарстане
because there is a Kadyrov battalion
потому что есть батальон Кадыров
in Tatarstan, they simply organized
в Татарстане просто организовали
Volunteers
Добровольцев
why so Who is involved in providing
почему так Кто занимается обеспечением
these battalions
этих батальонов
I don’t know, not the Ministry of Defense but the
не знаю вот не Министерство обороны а
local authorities That’s all I don’t know That
местные власти Вот и все Я не знаю То
is, see Chechnya Chechnya if you look
есть смотрите Чечня Чечня если смотреть
after the start of the
после начала
special operation  so its subjectivity
спецоперации так свою субъектность
raised completely  Adyrov is almost 2
подняла полностью Кадыров чуть ли не 2
people in the state now, though
человек государстве сейчас правда
soon Delimkhanova is the last but not the
скоро делимханова последняя но и не
second Yes, and soon Delimkhanova will appoint
второй Да и скоро делимханова назначит у
you as the head of the National Guard, it will be
вас руководителем росгвардии будет
generally fun,
вообще весело
but what’s wrong is not just that I see that
а что плохого нет просто я смотрю что
national autonomies are so they live
национальные автономии так они обитают
subjectivity Russia center no longer
субъектность Россия центр уже не
controls these territories they  already in
контролирует эти территории они уже по
fact they are not already taken by the local authorities
сути их не местные власти уже берут себе
say that they control this has been
говорите что они контролируют это уже
happening for 20 years it’s not like that
происходит на протяжении 20 лет не так
See the fact that at least it’s getting
Смотрите дело в том что как минимум у
stronger for me
меня усиливается например то что
that they allow themselves
сейчас разрешают что они разрешают себе
and attacks, and for example, look in
и выпады и вот например смотрите в
Tatarstan how they renamed the group of
Татарстане как переименовали группу
Tatarstan,
Татарстана
I don’t even know if the president of the Republic of
я не знаю даже было президент Республики
Tatarstan was
Татарстан
your Duma adopted that the president of the type in
ваша Дума приняла чтобы президент типа в
Russia in the republics should not be called
России в республиках не назывались
presidents Yes,
президенты Да конфликт правительства
there is some kind of conflict between the government of Tatarstan, yes Raisa Rais is
Татарстана какой-то там да Раиса Раис
already underway  renaming even a fact is not this
уже идет переименование даже факт Не это
different already  even
другое уже даже
renaming to ethnic Yes,
переименование на этнические Да вот
such things have
такие вещи
lost their solidity, they all
утратила свою монолитность все она
held on to bayonets, the army The personnel
держалась на штыках армия Кадровая
died in Ukraine in the first month, now the
погибла в Украине в первый месяц сейчас
army is shutting up with these
армия затыкается вот этими там
voluntary local
добровольными типа местными
regional battalions, which, in
региональными батальонами которые по
fact, now they will become the regional
сути сейчас Икс они станут региональными
armies of sovereign republics, that's all
армиями суверенных республик вот и всё
Therefore  I really like the process in the
Поэтому мне очень нравится процесс в
Russian Federation, everything goes to the point that
Российской Федерации все идет к тому что
in the Eighties, to say that the
в Восьмидесятых годах сказать то что
Soviet Union would fall apart was
Советский Союз развалится было
like a fantasy, and then once and
типа фантастика да потом раз и
fell down here and now to say a year
посыпалась вот и сейчас сказать год
ago that Russia would fall apart, everyone
назад что Россия развалится все
twisted around Whiskey And
покрутили у Виска А теперь
now why would all this be me  I was just
к чему бы это все я просто был
telling you I’m describing the future to you
рассказываю обрисовываю вам будущее
Let’s
Давайте
even if Russia falls apart
даже если Россия развалится
Ukraine will not be the best situation
Украина будет не самым лучшим положении
at the end of all this Why
в конце этого всего Почему
yes, you have already been beaten normally Well,
да у вас уже потрепали нормально Ну так
look Yes, the fact is that you, for example,
смотрите Да дело в том что вы например
will pay reparations Yes, well,
будете выплачивать репарации Да ну
Absolutely right So Russia will not
Абсолютно верно Так Россия же не будет
subjects that were Well, yes, not yet  no, the
субъекты которые были Ну еще да не будет
Americans will beat them up for you,
[__] подобьют их под себя вам вот
like this,
так вот
nothing will be used as
ничего не будет используется как
condoms, see I’m basically
презервативы смотрите Я вот в принципе
not strong in history But I looked where the
не силен в истории Но я смотрел куда вот
USSR and the USA went South Korea and
входило СССР и США Южная Корея и
North Korea where the USSR was
Северная Корея там где было СССР
North Korea is still there Ass  Where
Северная Корея там до сих пор [__] Там
there was America South Korea there
где было Америка Южная Корея там
for some reason transferring the country
почему-то передавая страна
technologically And why so
технологически А почему так
I don’t know what you call an [ __ ]
Я не знаю что вы называете жопой
abroad Western countries Today
за границей западных странах Сегодня
I can say I most likely
могу сказать Я скорее всего
But I can’t call Russia a complete [ __ ]
Но я не могу назвать Россию полной жопой
From some points of view an [ __ ] but not
С каких-то точек зрения [__] но не
full ass
полная [__]
just Americans us Americans
просто американцы нам американцы
Americans I see So you are completely
американцы я смотрю Так вы же полностью
dependent on the Americans
зависит от американцев
from the Americans than to start it cool And
от американцев чем завести это круто И
that Germany was so dependent on the USSR after the Second World
что Германия так после Второй Мировой
War the
войны
Federal Republic of Germany
Федеративная Республика Германия
depended on America as a result of the
зависела от Америки в результате
Independently rich in
Независимо богата
technology  developed and the GDR was from
технологически развита а ГДР было от
it became like the Soviet Union
стало как и Советский Союз
was before Ger  mania was possible to say
было до Германия была можно говорить
everything you see, that is, where where there is
все видите то есть там где там где
America there something bad does not happen so
Америка там что-то плохо не бывает так
No, I say it was what happened before this year
Нет я говорю была что было до этого года
it was what was Germany Germany Now
было что было Германия Германия Сейчас
everything flourished in it,
все процветала в ней было
and now in Germany everything is in decline Yes, so
а сейчас в Германии все упадок Да пока
far  there is still industry and then
что еще есть промышленность а потом
it most likely goes to the USA
она скорее всего едет в США
Why is
Почему это
it because it became unprofitable to produce
а потому что стало невыгодно производить
products in Germany it became
продукцию в Германии стало
uncompetitive why it was profitable
неконкурентноспособ почему было выгодно
because there were cheap resources cheap
потому что были дешевые ресурсы дешевые
energy sources And why then won’t it
энергоносители А почему тогда она не
move, for example, to some kind of Vietnam
переедет например в какой-то там Вьетнам
China Indonesia maybe  why is she in the
Китай Индонезии возможно почему она в
USA where the salary is expensive even
США там где Дорого короче зарплата даже
because right now the USA
потому что именно сейчас США тем кто
gives good benefits to those who move, in short,
переезжает дает хороший льготы короче я
after the war, it means Russia will fall apart
после войны значит Россия развалится
Ukraine will be bad because the USA
Украине будет плохо потому что США нам
will not help us And Germany
не будет помогать А Германия вообще
will generally be an ass because the USA will take everything from there
будет [__] потому что США заберет оттуда
ass  there it is unlikely that
все [__] там вряд ли будет
all the factories will be back
все заводы назад
for life
для жизни
once you support the war, but I'm
раз Вы поддержите войну А я вот
worried that in Ukraine everything would be  it was
переживаю чтобы на Украине все было
great, so I think it’s positive
прекрасно вот я думаю позитивно
Why, if you were worried about
Почему если вы переживали за то чтобы
everything being fine in Ukraine, you said
Украине было все прекрасно вы сказали
Crimea is Ukraine Yes, and not kiwi, but we
Крым это Украина Да и не киви а мы там
’ll take Kherson there and so on Why
заберем Херсон и так далее Почему я
should I think as you think, I
должен думать так как вы думаете вот я
think
так считаю
so, therefore I want you  you may want
поэтому я хочу Вы можете хотеть чтобы у
us to have everything, but I want
нас все было а я хочу так чтобы у нас
everything to be fine with us And you had a bad time, this is
все было хорошо А у вас было плохо это
normal
нормально
because you yours
потому что вы ваша ваша
want to talk
хотите поговорили
well moods did not come
хорошо настроения не пришли
When the Russian Federation collapses,
Когда развалится Российская Федерация
so
так
accept Pour champagne if you
примете Налейте шампанское если оно еще
still have it there  not Station Yes, have a
будет у вас там не Станционной Да
drink and tell me finally Pskov became
выпейте и скажите наконец Псков стал
free This dude from the Internet was right
свободным Это чувак с интернета был прав
Glory to Ukraine,
Слава Украине
so they don’t really argue anymore Yes, what will
так вот они уже не совсем спорят Да что
fall apart, Russia will fall apart and
там развалится развалится Россия и
many are skeptical Even in Ukraine
многие скептически Даже у нас в Украине
now what kind of collapse of Russia
сейчас какой развал России
six months ago they only talked about this
полгода еще назад в этом говорили только
there are some marginal circles there and
какие-то маргинальные там круги там и
certain analysts now Budanov already has a
определенные аналитики сейчас уже у
map of the section of
Буданова висит в кабинете карта раздел
Russia
России
Danilov publicly Peskov in his office  replies that
Данилов публично Пескова отвечает что
Ukraine Russia will disintegrate in America already,
Украина Россия распадется в Америке уже
too, many there are these tendencies that
тоже многие есть вот эти тенденция
sounds like the disintegration of Russia Russia itself already
звучит распаде России самой России уже
perceives when a year ago it
воспринимает когда год назад
tells something about the disintegration of Russia and
рассказывает что-то распаде России а
now they lost with the
теперь у
Solovyovs they are
Соловьев проиграли
discussing this map of dividing Russia
обговаривают эту карту раздела России
that a forum of the peoples of Russia has gathered in Europe
что в Европе собрался форум народов
so
России так
decolonization Sobchak  released there
деколонизации Собчак выпустила там
We also went home a video that Russia
Мы поехали домой тоже видео что Россия
may fall apart Khodorkovsky, who
может распасться Ходорковский который
was such a pepper so for United Russia,
был таким перцем так за Единую Россию
has also already stated that Russia may
уже тоже заявил что Россия Может
fall apart as a result of this war, so that is, all these ideas they already come to mind and you know what they
приходят в голову и знаете что они
should reach  Russians to people in
должны дойти до русских до людей в
Russia of Russian Chechens, many Buryats,
России русских чеченцев бурята многие
for example, in some republics are afraid.
например в некоторых республиках боятся
For example, if our republic becomes
Например если Наша республика станет
independent there, conditionally there is Tatarstan,
независимая там условно там Татарстан у
we have three million there, how will we live
нас там три миллиона как мы будем жить
if
если
independent, for example, Iceland, there are 300
независимое например Исландия там 300
thousand and somehow functions Yes, on the
тысяч и как-то функционирует Да на
world stage and  live better than in
мировой арене и живут лучше чем в
Tatarstan, why is Tatarstan with  its
Татарстане то почему Татарстан с его
resources Yes, you won’t be able to live and so
ресурсами Да не сможешь жить и так
on,
дальше
many people are simply afraid of changes, here a
многим людям просто страшны перемены вот
person can work at a job with a low
человек может работать работе с низкой
salary with a very low one, but appear to
зарплатой с очень низкой но появиться
look for some other
поискать какую-то другую О это хоть
one.  people are afraid of change,
чтобы Да вот и люди боятся изменений так
but we must also explain to people
но мы должны также объяснять для людей
here. Take Kazakhstan Yes, the Kazakhs in
вот Возьмите Казахстан Да казахи в
Kazakhstan live and develop, and the Kazakhs
Казахстане живут и развиваются а казахи
in Omsk to the Kazakhs in Orenburg, which
в Омске на казахи в Оренбурге который на
are the same Kazakhs, but they live on the
те самые казахи но они живут на
territory of Russia. They live, they are
территории России Они живут их
sent to war, this is in Ukraine and
отправляют на войнушку это в Украине и
so on, the same people alone
так дальше одни один тот же самый народ
if Kazakhstan was now not an independent
если Казахстан был сейчас не независимым
state And as part of Russia, also
государством А в составе России также
Kazakhs Now they would be taken from Almaty from
казахов Сейчас бы брали из Алматы из
Astana and thrown to death in Ukraine,
Астаны и бросали бы на смерть в Украине
and so the state Independently develops
а так государство Независимо развивается
in itself, everything Azerbaijan
в себе всё Азербайджан независимой
develops independently in its own way  yes
развивается себе в своём ключе да
ok so on
Окей так далее